我们现在已经实现了两个屏幕的线框图了
Okay. So now we have the wireframes implemented for both screens.
它在平板上会是什么效果呐  额…很不幸
But what does it look like on the tablet? Well, unfortunately,
当我们把手机界面伸展到平板时
when we take the phone UI and stretch it out on
它就看起来不怎么好了  有太多的空白部分
a tablet, it doesn't look that great. There's a lot of empty
我们可以充分利用屏幕的优势
white space here. We could better take advantage of this screen
去向用户展示更多有用的信息  举个栗子
real estate by showing more useful information. For example, why do the
这么大个屏幕  为啥要点开才能查看详细的
details need to be a tap away when they could just
天气情况呐  此外  如果用户
as easily fit on this screen? And, furthermore, if the user wants
要看一下整个列表项
to look through the full list of forecasts, their eyes
他们的眼镜必须横扫着看  这是很差劲的用户体验
must go like this, which is an unpleasant reading experience. If
如果我们想让用户去读一些内容的话  我们应该把
we want the user to read some content, we should keep
宽度设限  那样他们就可以快速的扫描阅读
the width narrower, so that they can scan it quickly. These
这些属于响应式设计范畴
considerations are part of responsive
响应式设计是  你的应用应该在不同
design. Responsive design means designing your
分辨率大小的屏幕下保持
app by keeping in mind that it'll be used across a
相同或者相近的用户体验  这个该怎么做呢
range of different device screen sizes. But how do we do
为平板这么大的设备适配
that, and what does it mean to build for larger screen
是什么意思呢  我可以为你展示一些实际例子
devices like tablets. Well, I can show you some examples of
看看这些应用是如何使用 Muti-pane 布局适配不同屏幕的吧  在Android设计指南里
how apps adapt using multi-pane layouts. In the Android Design Guide,
有一个部分叫 Muti-pane 布局  有一项方法就是  把多个视图
there's a section on multi-pane layouts. One technique is to combine
结合在一起  举个栗子  在联系人这个应用里  你有
multiple views together. For example, in the People app, you have
一个联系人列表和联系人详细信息卡片
the contact list and the contact card for additional details. On
在平板设备上  我们可以把他们各方一边  这是
the tablet, we can put them side by side. This is
我们熟知的 Master/Detail Flow  这个是主列表
also known as the master detail flow. This is the master
这个是详细页  在设置里
list and this is the detail pane. In the settings app,
我们还有另外一个栗子  选项列的宽是根据屏幕的宽度
we have another example. The column width adjust based on the
自适应的  在日历应用里  我们有很多 panel
available screen width. In the calendar app, we have panels, and
它们在屏幕纵向的时候是垂直叠放的
they stack vertically in the portrait orientation but horizontally in the
屏幕横向的时候是水平叠放的  这里还有其他一些个例子你可以去
landscape orientation. There also a couple of other examples that you
瞧一瞧  如果你想知道更多关于
can look through as well. If you want more information on
平板和响应式设计的话  你可以查看
designing for tablets or responsive design in general, you can check
课程视频下方的链接  在我们的系列课程里
out the links below for more details. In this course, we're
我们会先学习手机用户界面设计然后才是
learning how to build up the phone UI first, and then the
平板  事实情况是  当我们最初
tablet UI. But in reality, when we're designing
开始考虑它的设计的时候  就应该考虑到响应式设计
it, we thought about responsive design from day
当你自己做应用程序的时候
one. When you're building your own app, it's
千万不要把手机的用户界面设计完了
bad practice to just completely design and build
再去开始头脑风暴平板的
your phone app and then start to brainstorm
界面设计  因为平板的界面通常会被手机
about the tablet UI. That's because the tablet
界面的设计所影响
UI often has an impact on the phone
包括产品的架构等
design, as well as the architectural decisions made here.